"妙警贼探" 前情提要...
Previously on White Collar...
Mosconi法典
The Mosconi Codex.
你要帮我偷回来
You're gonna steal it for me.
何时才结束?
When does it end?
你把流血不止的他留在了人行道上
You left him bleeding on the sidewalk.
我没杀那家伙
I didn't kill the dude.
我拿了他的证件 把枪丢进了垃圾桶 我发誓
I pulled that badge and gun out of the trash, I swear.
Summers告诉我们把两百万美金藏在哪了
Summers told us where she hid the $2 million,
但却找不到
but it wasn't there.
- 推拿诊疗室?  - 看上去有模有样
- A chiropractor's office?  - It'll look the part.
我是Gruetzner探员 恭候多时
Agent Gruetzner. We've been expecting you.
有什么原因吸引他来这吗?
Any reason he'd slip away to come here?
Neal来一定是有原因的
Neal always has a reason.
如果这本书是一副拼图
If this book is a puzzle,
这些可能是拼块
maybe these are the pieces.
这个彩绘玻璃窗
This stained glass window
肯定就在曼哈顿
could be right here in Manhattan.
Neal就站在这
This is where Neal was standing.
根据他的脚铐记录
For 20 minutes,
20分钟后
after which he went straight home,
他就直接回家了
according to his anklet.
从这个十字路口 你可以监视到一个博物馆
From this intersection, you could scout a museum,
两个银行 一个画廊
two banks, and a gallery,
更别说其它住宅区了
not to mention all the residential targets.
Peter 我打电话问过了
Peter, I made some calls.
没有可疑现象上报过来
There was no suspicious activity reported.
Neal Caffrey在这就够可疑的了
Not unless you count Neal Caffrey being here.
你觉得是我反应过度吗?
You think I'm overreacting?
不 我只是觉得我们也许可以考虑
No, I just think we might consider the possibility
Caffrey只是去买点东西的可能性
that Caffrey was just picking up some groceries.
为了买面包 这也未免太远了
Long walk for a loaf of bread.
好吧
Okay.
那他在那里干嘛?
So what was he doing there?
首先 有失踪的现金
First, there was the missing cash,
然后在推拿诊疗室找到一支联邦调查局的笔
then the FBI pen at the chiropractor's office,
现在是这个街角
and now this street corner.
那你认为全部加起来的结果是?
So what do you think it all adds up to?
这就是问题
That's the problem.
我找不到关联点
I can't see how it all connects.
还缺点什么线索
I'm missing something.
看看这个地方的监控录像有没有拍到什么
See if any cameras in the area picked up anything.
好的
Will do.
听着 我也查了下
Listen, I also ran the card
你在Siegel证件里找到的卡片
that you found in Siegel's badge.
跟房地产公司谈过
Talked to the real estate company.
没人知道"cooper 3?"是什么
No one knew what "cooper 3?" meant.
我查过了Siegel的旧案件夹
I looked through Siegel's old case files,
以及在芝加哥的朋友 家人
friends and family back in Chicago.
天啊 我甚至谷歌过了
Hell, I even looked on google.
都没找到线索 抱歉
No hits. Sorry.
听着 我实在不想开口问这个
Listen, I hate to ask you this,
你认为Caffrey没有完全告诉我们
but you don't think Caffrey knows anything
他知道的事情 对吧?
that he's not telling us, do you?
- 关于Siegel的事?  - 对
- About Siegel?  - Yeah.
- 是的  - 好吧
- I don't.  - All right.
查过黑市的暗号
Checked black market code words,
不同的地方 线人名字
drop locations, C.I. names.
Mozzie甚至把它和劫机大盗联系起来了
Mozzie even tried to tie it to D. B. Cooper.
还是没查到
Nothing.
可能是一个联邦调查局探员的救命稻草
Maybe it's an FBI agent grasping at straws.
嘿
Hey.
我们都知道你的直觉很少会错
We both know your instincts are rarely wrong.
目前我们有个被窃的运货箱
Well, for now, we've got a stolen shipping crate
要高度重视
that demands our attention.
一个诈骗汽车货运公司今天早上
Grabbed from Canadian customs this morning
从加拿大海关拿过来的
by a fraudulent trucking company.
司机跑掉了 还没找到他
The driver ran. No sign of him yet.
肯定是一些加拿大走私货
Must be some exotic Canadian contraband
好让你走出办公室
to get you out of the office.
那可值得我伸展拳脚
Oh, this is well worth a stretch of my legs.
别告诉我
Don't tell me.
是来自西北地区
It's diamonds from the Diavik Mine
戴维科钻石矿场的钻石
in the northwest territories.
可能是枫蜜呢
Maybe it's maple syrup.
你说笑吧 加拿大枫糖浆抢劫大案
You joke, but the great Canadian maple syrup heist
值1800万呢
was worth 18 million.
那要找大点的箱了
You'd need a bigger crate though.
需要很多薄饼
And a lot of pancakes.
我是特别探员Burke 开箱吧
Special Agent Burke. Go ahead.
好像圣诞节的早上
It's like Christmas morning.
不 这不是礼物 是赃物
No, it's not a gift. This is stolen property.
我知道这条界限对你来说模糊
I know the line gets blurry for you.
根据箱子的大小和原产国
Based on the size of the box and the country of origin,
我的最佳猜测是Emanuel Hahnd的雕塑品
my best guess is a sculpture from Emanuel Hahn,
加拿大艺术家 大约在1918年
Canadian artist, circa 1918.
这比圣诞节礼物还牛
Oh, this is better than Christmas.
是枚恐龙蛋
This is a dinosaur egg.
到现在了你还有点想看它裂开 对吧?
Even now you kind of expect it to crack open, don't you?
我真不想
I really don't.
一颗化石蛋竟然没有引起你的幻想?
A fossilized egg doesn't capture your imagination?
它的价值倒是引起了
Well, the value of it does.
你好? 打扰下
Hello? Excuse me.
我是Khatri博士
I'm Dr.Khatri.
我是自然历史博物馆的馆长之一
I'm one of the curators of the natural history museum.
我是Peter Burke探员
Agent Peter Burke.
就是你帮我找回了恐龙蛋
You're the one who found my egg.
也不是他一个人的功劳
Well, he can't take all the credit.
它的母亲在哪?
And where's the mother?
什么意思?
What do you mean?
那个母亲装在另一只箱子里
There was a second shipment containing the mother.
什么母亲?
What kind of mother?
一只霸王龙
A Tyrannosaurus Rex.
你是说有一只霸王龙
You're saying there's a Tyrannosaurus Rex
在纽约失踪了?
lost somewhere in New York city?
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 伊娃 初见 爱鼠影 卡夫横 捞小盐
校对: 爱鼠影
妙警贼探 第五季第8集
霸王龙被同时用另一辆货车
Tyrannosaurus Rex was being shipped simultaneously
运过来了
on a different truck.
找不到在哪儿
No sign of it anywhere.
追捕一只霸王龙啊
Hunting a T-Rex.
如果是7岁的我 一定会高兴疯了
Seven-year-old me would be going crazy.
长大成人的你也不是很淡定啊
Adult you isn't exactly serene.
我迫不及待想亲眼看到它
I can't wait to see it in person
和它的蛋团聚
when it's reunited with its egg.
Mozzie以前经常做假的化石
Mozzie used to create fake fossils
然后埋到考古挖掘场
and bury them at dig sites.
以前经常?
Used to?
几个月之前的事了
It's been a couple months.
Mozzie创造了地球的历史
The alternate history of the earth according to Mozzie.
太可怕了
That's terrifying.
我是说 黑市上的假化石
I'm just saying, the black market is rife
俯拾皆是
with fake fossils like this.
我们知道这个蛋是真的吗?
Do we know the egg is real?
Khatri做了一个重要的测试 而且已经验证了
Khatri ran an acid test and authenticated it.
那些超级有钱 但是不够精明的人
Well, people with way too much money and no subtlety
就喜欢放在他们的办公室
do love to put them in their office
炫耀权力
as a display of power.
对 有什么比一只霸王龙和它的蛋更牛吗?
Yeah, what bigger display than a T-Rex and its egg?
无论买方是谁
Whoever the buyer is,
他们肯定会要整套的
it's clear they want the entire set.
单独一个很珍贵 一起就是无价之宝了
Valuable alone, invaluable together.
就像玛丽女王的钻石项链
It's like having Queen Mary's diamond riviere
没有了漫游者珍珠
without the la peregrine pearl.
Jones在查嫌疑犯清单上的人
Jones is working on a list of suspects.
我得回家了 今晚有什么打算吗?
I gotta get home. What are your plans tonight?
我回家放松下
I'm just gonna relax at home.
随便读点书
Do a little light reading.
嘿
Hey.
很开心你打给我了
I'm really happy that you called.
我发现了点东西 也带来了点东西
I found something, and I brought something.
是啊 我该早点跟你说...
Yeah, I should've mentioned...
Gruetzner探员会和我们一起
Agent Gruetzner will be joining us.
你好
Hello.
珍本书专家和红酒专家
A rare book expert and a wine connoisseur.
是加州津芬德尔葡萄酒
Oh, California zin.
还真是技多不压身
Well, there's no shame in having one specialty.
你说发现了什么?
You said you found something?
对
Uh, yes.
对 我发现了点东西
Yes, I did.
我在调查彩绘玻璃窗的时候
So I was looking into the stained glass window,
无意中发现了这个
and I stumbled across this.
哇
Oh, wow.
那是Mosconi的墓地
Oh! Mosconi's grave site.
对
Uh, yes.
看看墓碑底部
Just look down here at the bottom.
是一个共济会的指南针
It's a masonic compass.
所以他是一个共济会会员
So he was a mason.
我早就该发现这点
I should have noticed it sooner.
这就是为什么他把第13章放到
I mean, this is why he put the Chapter 13
法典里
into the codex.
13被认为是手足情谊的神圣数字
13 is considered a sacred number for the brotherhood.
他在向其他共济会会员传达信息
He was sending a message to the other masons.
法典可以指引我们了解任何事情
The codex could lead us anywhere.
共济会会员手上什么都有
I mean, masons have their hands in everything.
财政 政府 艺术
Finance, government, art.
英年早逝
Untimely death.
看墓碑上的日期
Look at the date on the gravestone.
1887年4月17日
April 17, 1887.
他也是在那个月画完玻璃窗的
That's the same month he finished the window.
那肯定是他最后的作品
That must have been his final work.
你认为他之所以被杀
Do you think that he was killed
是因为这些吗?
because of all of this?
如果是的话
If that's so,
彩绘玻璃窗就能告诉我们原因了
the stained glass could tell us why.
谢谢提供这些信息 我们会从这里着手
Well, thanks for everything. We'll take it from here.
噢
Oh.
好的 你们接手吧
Okay, I'll leave you to it.
好 谢谢你过来 还带了红酒
Yes, thank you for coming over and for the wine.
别客气
Sure.
愿意周三和我吃晚饭吗?
Dinner on Wednesday without the chaperone?
我愿意奉陪 Gaffrey探员
Of course, Agent Gaffrey.
期待和你合作
I look forward to working with you more
调查整个案件
on all of this.
什么?
What?
完全在我的掌控下
I got it under control.
我不想说显而易见的事情
Well, I hate to report the obvious news,
但你现在一点也不掌控自如
but the last thing you are right now is under control.
幸好你有个守护天使
Luckily, you have a guardian angel
眷顾着你
looking over you.
这不像天使做的事 更像跟踪狂
This is less angel and more stalker.
我查过她的底了
I vetted her,
粗略查了一下
a cursory audit.
资金 教育背景 日程安排
Financials, education, daily schedule.
她日程安排紧凑 会讲三种语言
She keeps a tight routine, speaks three languages,
在法国留学了两年
studied two years in France.
拿着这个 以防万一
Here, just keep it. Just in case.
霸王龙和她的蛋被一个住在多伦多的人
T-Rex and her egg were owned legally
合法拥有50年了
by a man in Toronto for 50 years.
直到三个月前他去世
He kept it in his family room
一直存放在他家里的休息室
until he died three months ago.
那可是会吃掉小孩的恐怖宠物
That's a hell of a pet to get your kids.
要多大的铲子来清理粪便啊
Big pooper scooper.
他口述过 去世之后
He dictated that, upon his death,
就捐给博物馆
it be donated to the museum.
我猜有人会说服中介
I'm guessing someone tried to persuade the estate
把它们卖掉
to sell it instead.
这样的人多着呢
Lots of someones.
都有哪些嫌疑人?
Who do we like?
有非常多的人
Well, there's a number of people
都很想收购它
who pursued it very aggressively.
竞价越来越高
Lots of escalating offers.
还有很多可疑分子去扰乱人心
And a lot of suspicious people making them.
有谁只出场过一回吗?
Anyone only try once?
有两个人只竞价过一次
Yeah, there were two single bids.
其中一个人出价很低
I mean, one was a lowball offer,
而另一个人
but then there's this guy.
他首次出价就比所有人都高
He made a single high-priced offer, then nothing.
Brett Forsyth 专门收购公司
Brett Forsythe, corporate raider,
通过恶意收购赚了几千万
made millions from hostile takeovers.
我听说过他
I've heard of him.
他去年带头收购了一家叫Aegis的公司
He led a takeover of a company called Aegis last year.
他是那种
That's the kind of guy
明知道别人不会卖
who knows when someone's not gonna sell,
还是会不择手段达到目的的人
and his only option is to take what he wants.
我要去会会他
I'm gonna pay him a visit.
不好意思 Forsythe先生现在不见客
I'm sorry, Mr. Forsythe is unavailable at the moment.
好吧
Of course he is.
那你就告诉他
Well, if you could tell him
联邦调查局精英调查小组的
that Agent Burke of the FBI,
Burke探员来访
White Collar Division,
想和他聊两句
would like to speak with him.
多久我都会等的
I can wait here as long as it takes.
反正有他们俩陪我
I'm sure these guys would love to keep me company.
很可能是她老板
That's probably her boss
说他可以见我了
telling her that I can see him now.
你接手Aegis公司的时候
When you took over Aegis,
董事会还不知道你要夺走他们的公司
the board didn't know you'd stolen their company
直到你走进会议事
until you walked through the door
宣布他们都被解雇了
and fired all of them.
那是我的合法权益 Burke探员
That was my legal right, Agent Burke.
是的
It was.
那后你就把公司拆分成一块一块地卖出去
And then you sold off pieces of the company one by one,
获得了一大笔利益
made a great profit.
很多人丢了工作
Lost a lot of jobs.
一个月前政府因为Aegis接管案已经找我问过话了
The feds questioned me about the Aegis takeover a month ago.
那件事完全合法
It was all aboveboard.
我知道
I know.
那你来是为了什么?
Why are you here?
那是迅猛龙的头骨吗?
Is that a velociraptor skull?
是的
Yeah.
我应该卖掉它
I should sell it.
因为侏罗纪公园
Thanks to Jurassic Park,
每个人都变成了恐龙爱好者
everyone thinks they're an expert on them.
但是那部电影里有很多错误
Except the movie got everything wrong.
迅猛龙很可能
Velociraptors were
是有羽毛的
most likely feathered,
因为古生物学家
based on the quill knobs
在它们身上发现了羽茎瘤
found by paleontologists.
而且电影把它们塑造得太大了
And the film made them much larger,
应该和恐爪龙的大小差不多
more like the size of a deinonychus.
没错
That's true.
迅猛龙其实和小鸡的大小差不多
Velociraptors were closer to the size of a chicken.
而且是长得很凶的小鸡
Still, one mean-looking chicken.
它们很危险
And very dangerous.
你也喜欢收藏?
Are you a collector?
就用政府给我的那点工资?
Oh, on a government salary?
连一个踝关节骨都买不起
I'd barely be able to afford an ankle joint.
你怎么得到它的?
How'd you get it?
有很多合法渠道可以买到化石
There are many legal ways to purchase fossils, Agent.
是的
True.
也有很多不合法的渠道
Many illegal ways as well.
这就是你来这里的原因?
That why you're here?
调查我的迅猛龙化石是否是合法取得的?
To question the legality of my velociraptor?
不 我要找的是个更大的家伙
No, I'm hunting something bigger.
霸王龙
A T-Rex.
你不是说你不喜欢收藏
Thought you said you weren't a collector.
不是我要找
It's not for me.
它本来应该在博物馆的
It was supposed to go to a museum
但现在却不见了
but didn't make it there.
Burke探员 退一万步说
Agent Burke, even if I stole a tyrannosaurus rex,
假设是我偷了霸王龙
which I did not,
我要它干嘛用呢?
what would I do with it?
我又不能把它摆在这里当装饰
It's not like I could just put it on display.
有道理
That's a good point.
但它还是很值得拥有的
But what a thing to have.
你认为他在自家衣柜里藏了一副骨架?
You think he has an actual skeleton in his closet?
我不知道那里藏了什么
I don't know what he's hiding in there,
但是龙头骨下面
but there was a large open space
确实有一大块空地方
right underneath the raptor skull.
你去的时候 他拖延了时间
Well, he stalled when you got there.
其实是在搬东西
That gave him time to move it.
很可能是违法的东西
So chances are it's illegal.
我敲门的时候
Is that what takes you so long
你需要那么长时间开门吗?
to come to the door when I knock?
你觉得我往床下藏违法的东西?
You think I'm hiding illicit goods under my bed?
你肯定是在藏着什么
I think you're hiding something.
但我没有足够的证据
But I don't have enough for a warrant
申请搜查Forsythe的办公室
to search Forsythe's office.
那你就等着瞧 看看有没有发现
You should stake it out, see what happens.
特别是晚上六点的时候
Especially around 6:00 p.m.
任何可疑情况我都会注意的
I'll keep an eye out for anything suspicious.
你说的空地方是在恐龙头骨下面?
You said the empty space was near the raptor skull?
嗯 正下方
Yeah, right underneath.
现在里面有东西了
It's not empty anymore.
是一个长得很丑的大棒子
Now there's a mean-looking club there.
像是前哥伦布时期的
Looks pre-Columbian.
Forsythe一定是在我离开之后放回去的
Forsythe must have moved it back after I left.
既然都来了
As long as I'm here,
那我就看看他都藏了些什么
I should see what else he's hiding.
不行 拍好照片赶紧出来
No, get the picture, and get out.
滑动锁的好处在于
The trick with sliding locks
上面的手印会告诉你密码是什么
is they leave a smudge that can tell you what the code is.
你听起来可没再往外撤
This does not sound like you getting out.
关键是要找出数字的排列顺序
The key is guessing where it starts and where it ends.
他是左撇子还是右撇子?
Is he right or left-handed?
右撇子 怎么了?
Right. Why?
右撇子的人
Right-handed people
习惯性的按逆时针方向
instinctively draw counterclockwise.
我让你赶紧出来
I told you to get out.
后面有Forsythe的整个实验室
Forsythe has a whole lab back here.
里面有显微镜 试管
Microscopes, test tubes,
所有鉴定的仪器设备
all kinds of forensic equipment.
Forsythe回来了
Forsythe came back.
快好了
Almost done.
你是不是触发警报了?
Did you set off an alarm?
Peter 这话可真伤人
Peter, that's hurtful.
他正往你那边走
Either way, he's headed your way.
好了 这就走
All right, leaving now.
你在哪?
Where are you?
它叫双刃刀
It's called a macuahuitl.
"双人刀"
"Macua-neenle."
- 不 是"双刃刀"  - "双淫刀"
- No, "macua-heetle."  - "Macua-heednum."
- 不 是"双刃刀"  - 我就是这么说的
- No, "macua-heetle."  - I said that.
好吧 不管怎么说 你猜得对
Okay, either way, your hunch is right.
它是在纽约一次前哥伦布时期
It was stolen from a pre-Columbian exhibit
展览中被偷的
here in New York.
我猜Forsythe一直都在
I guess Forsythe does some business
和黑市做生意
in the black market after all.
但你要知道 它是很多年前被偷的
Yeah, but get this. It was stolen eight years ago.
诉讼时效已经过了
Statute of limitations is up.
Forsythe是个聪明人
Forsythe's a smart guy.
他知道我们不能因此抓他
He knows we can't get him on it.
当然了 他可不想
Sure, he didn't want to raise
在老虎的屁股上拔毛
a red flag in front of a bull.
但他在谋划一个更大的阴谋
Not when he's hiding something bigger.
像霸王龙这样的大活
For a job as big as a T-Rex,
他想找一个他信任的人
he'd wanna use somebody he can trust,
一个他打过交道的人
somebody he'd used before.
双刃刀的小偷有线索吗?
Any suspects in the macuahuitl theft?
没人被捕 但嫌疑人一共三个
There were no arrests, but there were three suspects.
一个在监狱里
One's in jail.
一个最近在布拉格被审讯
One recently questioned in prague.
最后是这家伙 Michael Holt
Then there's this guy, Michael Holt.
是东海岸的四宗抢劫案的嫌疑人
Suspected in four other robberies along the east coast.
他从不在一个地方久住
He doesn't stay in one place very long.
但就算是一个偷盗大师
No, but even a master thief needs time to unload
装卸40英尺高的恐龙化石也需要时间
a 40-foot prehistoric skeleton.
最起码在他离开纽约之前
Either way, we've got a narrow window
我们的怀疑范围缩小了
before he leaves town.
查一下他的踪迹
Track him down.
在此之前
Before we do,
你想不想知道Caffrey为什么
you wanna know why Caffrey
要在那个街角站着吗?
was standing on that street corner?
想知道
Yeah, I do.
你有什么线索?
What do you have?
不是东西 而是一个人
Not what. It's who.
我从街对面的监控录像里截下来的
I got this off a security camera from across the street.
她看着很眼熟
She looks familiar.
她叫Rebecca Lowe
Her name's Rebecca Lowe.
没错 就是之前Gershon失窃案
Yeah, the woman we brought in
我们带回来讯问的女人
from the Gershon heist a while back.
Neal和她在一起干什么?
What's Neal doing with her?
要知道 我跟El聊过
You know, I was talking to El,
她有个朋友想介绍你认识
she has a friend she'd like to set you up with.
这位朋友知道我有犯罪记录吗?
Does this friend know that I come with a rap sheet?
知道 有兴趣吗?
Uh-huh. Interested?
替我跟Elizabeth道谢 但我目前不想找女朋友
Tell Elizabeth thank you, but I'm not looking right now.
Sara离开也有段时间了
Well, it's been a while since Sara,
我觉得你也许会想开始新恋情
and I thought you might wanna get back out there.
我并不是指这对你来说很困难
Not that it's difficult for you.
你会惊讶的
You'd be surprised.
只要是和我恋爱的人 我都得跟她撒谎
Anyone I date, I have to lie to
或者猜测她为什么对个罪犯有兴趣
or wonder why she's interested in a felon.
就没遇上例外?
No luck at all?
Jones 怎么了?
Yeah, Jones?
去哪儿?
Where to?
好的
Yeah.
好 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
Holt跑了
Holt's gone.
Jones查了他的信用卡记录
Jones checked his credit cards.
他买了张机票逃出国了
He bought a plane ticket out of the country.
我会用自己的名字和信用卡买机票的
The only reason I'd buy a plane ticket under my name
唯一企图就是我想让别人误以为
with my credit card is if I wanted someone
我逃出国了
to think I'd left the country.
航空公司确认他登机了
The airline confirmed that he got on the plane.
航空公司只是确认了拿着Holt机票的人
The airline confirmed someone with Holt's ticket
登机了
got on the plane.
你记得那次你误以为我在摩纳哥吗?
You know that time you thought I was in Monaco?
别告诉我 我让国际刑警
Don't tell me that I had Interpol
搜索街道完全是无用功
scouring the streets for nothing.
我用自己的名字买了张头等舱机票
Bought a first-class ticket under my name
然后换了登机牌
and checked in for my flight.
等我到了登机口
Once I got to the gate,
就会找一个单独坐飞机 还只带了随身行李的人
I looked for someone traveling alone with a carry-on.
如果有人托运了行李
If someone checks a bag
但没上飞机
and doesn't get on the plane,
飞机就不会起飞
the flight doesn't take off.
然后我把机票送给他
So I offer them my ticket,
对方一定会收
which of course they're gonna take
因为一个要飞三千英里的正常人
because no sane person facing a 3,000-mile trip
是不会拒绝头等舱机票的
is gonna say no to a seat in first class.
他们不会怀疑进一步的目的?
And they don't suspect an ulterior motive?
并不是所有人都和你一样生性多疑 Peter
Not everyone is as naturally suspicious as you, Peter.
我的多疑天性可是
My nature has developed
常年分析你的可以行径得来的
from years of tracking your suspicious behavior.
所以这个陌生人没有生疑
So this unsuspecting stranger
拿了你的机票登机...
gets your ticket, gets on the plane...
然后Neal Caffrey的机票就去了摩纳哥
And Neal Caffrey is on his way to Monaco,
而真的Neal Caffrey就悄悄溜了出来
while the real Neal Caffrey slips out of the gate unnoticed.
不敢相信 你竟然不知道
I can't believe you never knew that.
监控拍到Michael Holt
Cameras caught Michael Holt
溜出了机场安检区
scoping out their security system.
他还想偷那枚蛋
He's still after that egg.
他觉得蛋在博物馆
He thinks it's at the museum.
抓Holt现行是我们追查
Catching Holt in the act is our best shot
失窃霸王龙的最佳机会
at tracking down that stolen T-Rex.
我会让监视小组
I'll put surveillance teams
全天候监视博物馆的
outside the museum around the clock.
- 随时向我汇报  - 好的
- Keep me posted.  - All right.
看来有人享受了头等舱的机票
Well, I guess someone else enjoyed that first-class ticket.
所以...
So...
Holt有了五十万的理由留下来
Holt had 1/2 million good reasons to stay.
你怎么知道Forsythe会付钱给Holt?
How did you know what Forsythe was gonna pay Holt?
我在密室里发现了装满钱的手提箱
I found a briefcase full of cash in his back room.
你开了密室?
And you opened it?
听着 这就是我生性多疑的原因
See, this is the reason I have a suspicious nature.
之后我得好好数数那箱钱
I'm gonna count every penny of it.
我没怪你 你应该如此
I don't blame you. You should.
只是大致估计了一下
It was a rough estimate though.
- 好吧  - 肯定是个整数
- Oh.  - It's a round number.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, hon.
怎么了?
Yeah?
今晚想来个四人约会吗?
How'd you like to go on a double date tonight?
跟Trey和Sheila一起?
With Trey and Sheila?
是Neal
Neal.
- 他知道我们要去吗?  - 你说呢?
- Does he know we're coming?  - Mm?
所以他不知道我们要去
He doesn't know we're coming.
他一直偷偷和这个女人在一起
He's been sneaking around with this woman,
我觉得他肯定在计划什么
and I think he's up to something.
也许他只是在和个美女享用美食
Or maybe he's having a nice meal with a nice girl.
那Neal就没理由瞒着我了
There's no reason for Neal to keep this from me.
他要和姑娘约会 我怎么会在意?
What do I care if he's going on a date with a girl?
显然你很在意
Clearly you care quite a bit.
肯定没这么简单
Nah, there's more to it than this.
Neal最近的行为非常不正常
A lot of things Neal has been doing don't add up,
而我的直觉告诉我 她就是关键
and my gut tells me she's at the center of it.
根据他脚铐的数据
Now according to his anklet,
他们现在在Clifton餐厅
they're at the Clifton.
你知道我一直很想去Clifton餐厅的
You know I've always wanted to go to the Clifton.
真的?
Really?
你觉得这是个好主意?
You think this is a good idea?
没错
I do.
我觉得你可能会喜欢这个
Thought you might like this.
红酒很不错
The wine is lovely.
这让我想起了今年夏天
And it reminds me of this summer
我在法国念书的日子
that I spent in France studying.
我记得我去过这个酒庄
I actually think I've been to this vineyard.
真的?
Really?
真的
Really.
你是不是利用联邦调查局的资源调查过我?
Did you have the FBI run a background check on me?
联邦调查局和这顿晚餐无关
The FBI had nothing to do with this dinner.
我保证
I promise.
要知道 你从未告诉过我
Hmm, you know, you never told me
你怎么会成为联邦调查局探员的
why you became an FBI agent.
我想肯定不止是用来泡妞那么简单
I assume it wasn't only to pick up women.
一个爱好艺术的人 怎么会变成两帮调查局探员的?
How does an art lover become an FBI agent?
说来话长
Eh, it's a long story.
我这辈子一直在研究古文字
I spend my life studying ancient texts.
所以不介意冗长的故事
I don't mind long stories.
我只是想两个人私下好好吃顿晚饭 好吗?
I want this dinner to be about you and me, okay?
我们不用谈论工作的事情
We don't need to talk about work.
好吧
All right.
我真的很喜欢这地方
I really do like this place
喜欢这红酒 法典
and the wine and the codex
还有你的吻
and the kiss.
我也挺喜欢的
I liked that part too.
要知道 你...
You know, you...
要是想让我帮忙查案
you don't have to do all this
其实不必做这些
just to get my help on the case.
你真觉得我是这种人吗?
Do you really think I would do that?
不
No.
那你觉得我是怎样的人?
What kind of guy do you think I am?
我不知道 你可是个联邦调查局探员
I don't know. You're an FBI agent.
没错
Yeah.
如果太复杂了 我能理解
If it's too complicated, I'll understand.
你是在给我找台阶下吗?
Are you trying to give me a way out?
显然还不够巧妙
Apparently without much subtlety.
不
No.
我不需要
I don't want one.
你呢?
Do you?
不
No.
嘿 Neal?
Neal?
Peter 你怎么来了?
Peter, what are you doing here?
Elizabeth一直很想来这儿吃饭
Elizabeth has been dying to try this place out.
嗨 我叫Peter 是Neal的上司
Hi, I'm Peter, Neal's boss.
我们见过 我是Rebecca
We've met. I'm Rebecca.
你差点逮捕我
You almost arrested me.
没错 非常抱歉
Oh, right. Sorry about that.
不... 等等 我以为你上司是...
No, it's... Wait, I thought your boss was...
这位是Peter的妻子Elizabeth
And this is Elizabeth, Peter's lovely wife.
很高兴认识你
It's so nice to meet you.
真的很抱歉 打扰你们了
I'm really sorry for interrupting.
没关系
Oh, nonsense.
朋友间可没什么秘密 对吧?
No secrets between friends, right?
当然没有
Course not.
我都不知道那案子之后
I didn't know that you two had been in touch
你们还有联系
since the investigation.
你们查案时候认识的?
You guys met on a case?
没错 要知道
Oh, yeah, you know
有时候不经意间 工作
how sometimes your personal and professional lives
和私生活就会混在一起
just crash into each other without any notice.
其实我和Peter就是这么认识的
It's actually how Peter and I met.
哦
Oh.
没错 我记得他还偷偷动用了调查局的资源
Yeah, agency resources were involved from what I recall.
那可是光明正大的
It was completely aboveboard.
事实上 我们刚说到
Actually, we were just talking
Neal是怎么成为联邦调查局探员的
about how Neal became an FBI agent.
没错 但说来话长
Yeah, but it's a long story.
我也挺想听这个故事的
I know I'd love to hear that story.
我要去看看还有没有空桌
Um, I'm gonna go check and see if we can get a table.
你想跟我一起去吗?
Would you like to go with me?
让他们自己聊聊?
Maybe let the boys chat?
当然
Of course.
一会儿见
See you in a little bit.
你来这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
你是在跟踪我吗?
Did you follow me here?
你最好再她们回来之前
You have until they come back
给我解释清楚她怎么会觉得你是联邦调查局探员的
to explain why she thinks you're an FBI agent,
否则我就告诉她真相
or I'm telling her the truth.
我们查案时认识的
We met on a case.
我跟她说我为联邦调查局工作
I told her I work for the FBI.
她就以为我是个探员
She assumed I was an agent.
你也没纠正她 对吧?
And you didn't correct her, did you?
我觉得没理由
I didn't see any reason to.
因为你这是在假冒联邦警员
Because you're impersonating a Federal officer.
我以为技术上...
I suppose technically...
别说技术上 你就是在假冒
No, not technically. You are.
还有推拿诊疗室的笔
The pen, the chiropractor's office.
你就是用这些让她相信的
This is all to convince her of this story.
你...
You're...
你喜欢她 对吧?
You like her, don't you?
好吧
Huh.
撒谎还真是种奇怪的表现方式
Lying is a funny way of showing it.
她没把我当成罪犯看 懂吗?
She doesn't look at me like a criminal, okay?
我在她眼里
She looks at me
就跟El眼里的你一样
the way El looks at you.
我不想毁了这一切
I don't want to ruin that.
Neal 你朋友真不错
Neal, you have lovely friends.
他们真是不错 对吧?
Oh, aren't they great?
我们就不打扰你们俩了
We are gonna get out of your hair right now.
有空桌了 来吧 我们走
We got a table. Come on, let's go.
好
Sure.
你们俩还有很多要聊呢
You two have lots to talk about.
失陪一下
Excuse me one minute.
我是Burke探员
This is Agent Burke.
我是Khatri博士
It's Dr. Khatri.
有人闯进来了
Someone's here.
我不认识他
I don't recognize him.
保持冷静 博士
All right, remain calm, Doctor.
我们有探员在博物馆里
We have agents in the museum.
我没在博物馆
No, I'm not there.
我把蛋带到我的实验室做CT扫描
I took the egg to my lab to run a CAT scan.
挂了电话 找个安全的地方躲起来
Hang up and find someplace safe.
我们马上就过去
We'll be there soon.
Neal 我们得走了 Khatri博士有危险
Neal, we have to go. Dr. Khatri's in trouble.
纽约警局的人正赶来 不过我们更快
N.Y.P.D. is on the way, but we're closer.
我们没时间了!
We're running out of time!
告诉我在哪!
You better tell me where it is!
你觉得我是在开玩笑吗?
What, you think I'm playing games?
我不会给你的
I'll never give it to you.
是Holt
It's Holt.
我不想再说一遍
I'm not gonna ask again.
如果我们贸然闯进去 他会开枪的
If we go in with guns drawn, he might shoot her.
Khatri不会交出蛋的
Khatri's not giving up that egg.
我们得想办法
We gotta come up with something,
不然她死定了
or she's gonna get herself killed.
那该死的蛋在哪?
Where the hell is the egg?
它的母亲在哪? 你们对她做了什么?
Where is the mother? What have you done with her?
它只是颗蛋 告诉我在哪
It's just an egg. Tell me where it is.
没这么简单
It's so much more than that.
它是一个需要母亲的孩子
It is a child that needs to be with its mother,
给了你 我会良心不安的
and I'll be damned if I'll ever give it up to you.
那你去死吧
Have it your way.
博士 你有同位素的结果报告...
Doctor, do you have the isotopic results...
站那别动
Hold it right there.
我不想惹事 好吗?
I don't want any trouble, okay?
该死的蛋在哪?
Where is the damn egg?
我带你去拿
I'll show you.
不行 你不能给他
No, you can't give it to him.
我可不想为了一颗化石吃子弹 懂吗?
I'm not taking a bullet for a fossil, all right?
跟我来
Follow me.
就在这边
Right through here.
放开我!
Get off of me!
帮我一下
Give me a hand.
不是每个贼都自己带着手铐
Not every thief who brings their own handcuffs.
你很有想法
Very thoughtful of you.
Holt承认是Forsythe雇佣他
Holt confirmed that Forsythe hired him
来抢化石的
for the fossil heist.
那你怎么还不为了
So why are you not doing
可以找到恐龙而高兴?
an "about to get the dinosaur" happy dance?
因为他不知道恐龙在哪儿
Because he doesn't know where the dinosaur is located.
如果我们现在逮捕了Forsythe
And if we arrest Forsythe now,
我们就不可能找到霸王龙了
there's no guarantee we'll get the t-rex back.
我们的证据太过宽泛
And our evidence is largely circumstantial.
需要有力的证据
I want hard proof.
- 你想要恐龙  - 我当然想要
- You want the dinosaur.  - Damn right I do.
Khatri博士肯定很高兴听到这个
Dr. Khatri will be happy to hear that.
我刚刚从医院回来
Just got off with the hospital.
她没事
She's fine,
只是受了点惊吓
just a little shaken up.
我们现在只有一张牌可打
There's only one chip we can play right now.
那颗蛋
The egg.
我们可以在上面弄个追踪器
We can plant a tracker on it.
我敢说他会把蛋和霸王龙藏在一起
I bet he'll stash it with the t-rex fossils.
跟踪他 然后逮捕
Follow him, make a clean arrest.
我不想用蛋去引诱他
I don't wanna put the egg in play.
太珍贵 也太重要了
It's too valuable, too important.
哦
Oh.
幸运的是
Lucky for us,
我们有人有伪造化石的前科
we know someone with a history of forging fossils.
Khatri博士给了我一些
Dr. Khatri gave me fragments
方解石和沉积岩的碎块
of real calcite shell and sedimentary rock.
我要用大理石雕蛋中间的部分
I'll sculpt the core from alabaster.
- 黏合剂呢?  - 已经准备好了
- Adhesives?  - Already mixed.
我们开始吧
We should get started.
我想你不是真要我来吧?
I assume you don't mean the royal we?
好假设
A correct assumption.
好吧
Oh.
盐酸和碳化钙在一起
The hydrochloric acid is reacting perfectly
反应得很好啊
with the calcium carbonate in the shell.
我们做了一个恐龙蛋 Moz
We made a baby dinosaur, Moz.
就像父亲伪造胚胎一样
Ah, like father, like forged embryo.
每个都装上脚铐
Each with his own anklet.
至少Peter跟着这个
At least Peter won't be able
不会找上Rebecca
to follow this tracker to Rebecca.
自从上次倒霉晚餐后 你联系过她吗?
Oh, have you spoken to her since your ill-fated dinner?
我警告过你 Neal
I warned you, Neal.
你 生意 女人
You, business, and women.
邪恶铁三角 我知道
Unholy trinity, I get it.
你应该感激
Well, you can be grateful
猫咪探长没揭穿你的身份
that the Suit didn't expose your agent nom de guerre.
我是很感激
Well, I am.
Peter再深究怎么办?
What happens when Peter digs deeper?
会发现法典的事情
Could find out about the codex.
是啊 或者Hagen
Yeah, or Hagen.
小心点吧
Cause for concern.
记好了 结束才有新的生机
Keep in mind, to make an end is to make a beginning.
你认为我应该跟她结束?
You think I should end it with her?
托马斯·斯特尔那斯·艾略特说的(诺贝尔文学奖获得者)
That was T.S. Eliot.
但如果猫咪探长注意到Rebecca了
But if Rebecca is on big brother's radar,
那就是时候结束了
the timing could be right.
好吧 对教堂的事情有计划了吗?
All right, do we have a game plan for the church yet?
我正在计划
I'm working on it.
在大庭广众之下
But to steal the stained glass window
偷走彩绘色玻璃窗是很难的
will be difficult with so many witnesses.
是啊 这事情也不急
Well, that's a problem that can wait a day.
确实
Indeed.
今天我们重现了白垩纪
Today we revive the cretaceous period.
明天我们去偷也许
Tomorrow we steal a window
和疯子写的书有关联的玻璃窗
that could be connected to a bedlamite's tome.
这就是生活
C'est la vie.
不错啊
Not bad.
本来我想完事后送你
I was gonna give it to you after this,
如果你觉得它不好...
but if you don't think it's very good...
"不错"并不意味着"不好"
"Not bad" doesn't mean "not good."
也不意味着"好"
It doesn't mean "good."
我会送给能欣赏它的人
I'll give it to someone who can appreciate it.
不 这是联邦调查局资产 我想要就可以拿走
No, this is FBI property. I can take it if I want.
好了 连上追踪器了
Okay, the tracker's live.
一旦Forsythe拿走了蛋 我们会紧跟他
When Forsythe moves the egg, we'll be right behind him.
Neal 说说你的卧底身份是
Neal, tell us about your cover.
John Mcdowell 和Michael Holt是同伙
John Mcdowell. Accomplice to Michael Holt.
来着送蛋的
Here to deliver the egg
因为联邦调查局在调查Holt
because the FBI is looking into Holt,
他现在得低调行事
and he's laying low.
Holt已经承认了
Which was confirmed by Holt
他安排了和Forsythe见面
when he called Forsythe to set up the meeting.
我们会一直监听你
We'll have ears on you the whole time.
带着这样一件赝品 肯定不会有问题
With a forgery like this, you should be out quickly.
带着五百万啊
With 1/2 million in cash.
联邦调查局在调查Holt?
The FBI is investigating Holt?
我该担心吗?
Should I worry?
不用 只是一个探员
Nah, it's just one agent shaking every tree he can find
遍地撒网而已
to see what falls out.
他没有任何证据
He doesn't have anything.
但是为了安全起见 我代替Holt来
But to be safe, I'm here instead of Holt.
如果你不想要蛋的话
Hey, if you don't want the egg anymore,
我可以转卖给别人
I'm sure I can unload it somewhere else.
别 别 没事的
No, no, no, no. It's fine.
我想要看看
I wanna see it.
不错
Ha.
别急着动手 这还不是你的
Uh-uh. No, it's not yours yet.
除非你付我钱
Not till you pay me.
你太着急了
You're getting ahead of yourself.
我需要鉴定一下
I need to authenticate it first.
那就快点把
Let's get a move on.
抓紧时间
Ticktock.
方解石含量和卵石纹路看上去是对的
Calcite levels and pebble texture appear appropriate.
我想这是好消息
I assume that's good news.
大大的好消息
Oh, it very much is.
我想你这下可以付我钱了吧
Then I think this is the part where you pay me.
我会的
I will.
等我做最后一项测试
After one last test.
有太多次
Can't tell you how many times
三脚猫想要用假的文物
two-bit hustlers have tried to rip me off
从我这打劫
with fake artifacts.
所以CT扫描就很有必要
Which is where the CAT scan comes in handy.
他不会看到里面有胚胎
He won't see an embryo on a CAT scan.
但他会看到跟踪器
But he will see the tracker.
扫描会进行十分钟
The scan will take about ten minutes.
所以耐心等着
So settle in.
听着 我可不觉得这么件小事要花这么久
Look, I didn't think this was gonna be an all-day thing.
知道吗?
Okay?
你是担心扫描会出问题?
You worried the scan won't work?
不 我只是不懂
No, I just don't understand
之前做了那么多测试
what this thing is gonna show you
这玩意还能测出什么新花样
that all the other tests didn't.
能测出里面有什么
It'll show me what's inside.
或者没有什么
Or what isn't.
咱们得让Neal撤出来
We need to pull Neal out of there.
等等 Khatri博士应该有一份那个蛋的CT扫描图
Wait, Dr. Khatri should have a CAT scan of the egg.
我联系她看看能不能发一份过来
I'll call to see if she can send one to us.
听说过马克胡特吗?
You ever heard of a Macuahuitl?
不就是你手上正拿着的这件武器嘛
It's the weapon you're holding in your hands right now.
John 关于这件武器 你还知道什么呢?
What else can you tell me about this weapon, John?
特别是你面前这一件?
Anything about this one in particular?
八年前我跟Holt在纽约
I stole it for you eight years ago
合力为你偷来的
with Holt right here in New York.
而且你拿的姿势不对
You're holding it wrong.
不介意吧?
You mind?
早期的马克胡特在手柄顶端要宽两英寸
The early Macuahuitl handle is 2 inches wider at the top.
要这样拿
Hold it like this.
握得越紧 挥动越迅速
Better grip means a faster swing.
更好把控
More control.
你的建议不错
You're right.
说起来 我也偷过不少东西
You know, I've stolen a lot of things,
但极少是纯粹为了拥有而下手的
but I've rarely taken anything just to have it.
有朝一日值得一试
You should try it sometime.
马上就要扫到胚胎那里了
We should be at the embryo any moment now.
什么事?
Yeah?
他来这干什么?
Why is he here?
好吧
Fine.
我马上就到
I'll be right there.
谁来了?
Who's here?
那个联邦调查局探员 还不死心呢
That FBI agent. Still shaking his trees.
别担心 我来搞定他
Don't worry, I'll get rid of him.
Forsythe先生 多谢赏脸
Mr. Forsythe, thanks for seeing me.
我不会占用您太多时间
I won't take up much of your time.
这是Michael Holt 他是我们
Michael Holt, he's our prime suspect
在化石窃案中的主要嫌疑人
in the fossil shipment theft.
这跟我有什么关系?
What's it got to do with me?
我只是在想 他或许会来向您兜售
I was wondering if maybe he approached you on buying them.
这样啊 只要他联系我 我第一个告知你
Well, if he contacts me, you'll be my first call.
就等着您这句话呢
All I wanted to hear.
那就慢走不送了
Then you'll be on your way.
说起来 虽然迅猛龙的名字意思是"快手贼"
You know, even though their name means "speedy thief",
但它们的速度其实并没那么快
they say that the velociraptor wasn't particularly fast.
的确如此
That's true.
而且也不聪明
And that it was dumb.
我猜大脑的容量也不大
Yeah, not much room for a brain in there, I guess.
不过是一只迟缓 迟钝 长着巨齿的大鸡
One slow, dumb chicken with big teeth.
别碰那个头骨
Don't touch the skull.
这些牙齿您是怎么粘起来的?
How do you keep them glued in there?
环氧树脂还是廉价胶?
Epoxy or tacky?
Burke探员 别...
Agent Burke, don't...
看来你该用强力胶的
Guess you should've used superglue.
- 玩够了吗?  - 嗯
- Is that all?  - Mm-hmm.
抱歉弄坏了你的恐龙
Sorry I broke your dinosaur.
快看看
Well, will you look at that?
钱在公文包里
Money's in the briefcase.
很荣幸跟你做生意
Pleasure doing business with you.
趁着没人做的那些见不得人的事
The things people do when they think no one's watching.
就好比跟踪自己的朋友
Like following your friend to a first date
毁了他的首次约会?
and crashing it?
走吧
Come on.
让Forsythe见识见识联邦调查局是怎么看待自然选择的
Let's show Forsythe how the FBI handles natural selection.
就憋出这么一句?
You just think of that one?
嗯 出动吧
Yeah, on the way over.
你在这干什么?
What the hell are you doing here?
我想了想你说的话
I thought about what you said.
我想清楚了自己想要什么
I figured out what I wanna take.
你怎么跟我到这来的?
How'd you follow me?
那个小家伙告诉我的
That little guy told me where you were.
或者至少可以说是里面那个GPS追踪器的功劳
Or at least a GPS tracker we put inside it did.
走吧
Let's go.
打开
Open it up.
这是当真俘获了我的想象力
Okay, that definitely captures my imagination.
你想当古生物学家已经晚了
You know, it's not too late for you to be a paleontologist.
有些东西远观即可 距离产生美
Some things are better enjoyed from a distance.
正如大型盗窃案一般
Oh, like grand larceny.
你就没点正当合法的兴趣爱好吗?
Are all of your hobbies illegal?
国际象棋
I like chess.
你曾在联合广场兜售国际象棋
You hustled chess in Union Square.
Burke探员
Agent Burke.
Caffrey先生 跟我来
Mr. Caffrey, follow me.
你们得看看这个
You need to see this.
这就是她
Here she is.
她真是...
She's...
雄伟
majestic.
正因为你们俩
This mother and child reunion
这对母子才得以重聚
was only possible because of you two.
博物馆方面欠您一份人情
The museum is in your debt.
我倒是知道有人想要个全年免票
I know someone who would love a year-round pass.
Burke探员 您在我们这边有VIP资格
Agent Burke, you have VIP status here.
我们的大门一直向您敞开
Our doors are always open.
Peter Burke 你可是VIP啊 我们得给你搞个徽章
Peter Burke, VIP. We should get you a badge.
低调点 谢谢你 博士
Quiet. Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你
Thank you.
今晚来我家吃晚饭
Come by the house for dinner tonight.
El要做柠檬鲈鱼
El's cooking branzino.
柠檬鲈鱼 瞧瞧你多滋润
Branzino, look at you.
我的生活也可以很炫的
I can be fancy.
多谢邀请 但...
Thanks for the invitation, but...
不是邀请
It's not an invitation.
看来是命令了?
So it's an order?
晚上七点
7:00 p.m.
别迟到了 Caffrey探员
Don't be late, Agent Caffrey.
真是糟糕
Bad news.
又是一顿佳肴
Another amazing meal.
必须的 这可是出自你手
Well, it should be. It's your recipe.
当初应该在烧烤时露一手的
Should've thrown it on a barbecue.
千万别让他当副主厨
Never let him be sous chef.
其实他还是挺擅长烧烤的
He's actually very good on the barbecue.
好吧... Rebecca
So... Rebecca.
- 没错 Rebecca  - 你们想听什么?
- Yeah, Rebecca.  - What do you wanna know?
你告诉她一切了吗?
Have you told her everything?
一切?
Everything?
你为什么为联邦调查局工作?
Why you're working for the FBI?
- 你为什么戴着脚链?  - 她看到过吗?
- Why you're wearing an anklet?  - Has she seen it?
好吧 我只是在等待合适的时机
Okay, I was waiting for the right time.
不存在什么合适的时机 Neal
There's no right time, Neal.
如果我告诉她真相 你们觉得会怎么样?
What do you think happens if I tell her the truth?
时间拖得越久
The more time passes,
真相便越伤人
the more the truth will hurt.
如果你对她是真心的
If you really want this to work,
现在就告诉她
tell her now.
祈祷她会接受你
Pray she'll accept it.
你也这么觉得?
You agree?
如果你真的在乎Rebecca
If you really care about Rebecca,
她就有权了解真正的你
she deserves to know the real you.
好吧 那假如当初Peter跟你相识之初
Okay, if Peter had told you something like this
向你坦白了类似的情况 你会接受他吗?
when you first met, would you have accepted it?
老实说 Neal 我... 我不知道
Honestly, Neal, I... I don't know.
但我会希望选择是我自己做出的
But I'd want the choice to decide.
我相信Rebecca也同样如此
And so will Rebecca.
这个险你不得不冒
It's a risk you should take.
我简直不想问你这玩意是怎么搞来的
I don't wanna ask why you have that thing.
就在那儿 不拿白不拿
Mm, it was there for the taking.
谢了
Thank you.
别客气 干杯
You're welcome. Cheers.
- 干杯  - 嗯
- Cheers.  - Mmm.
Byron以前一直说这座城市会跟他对话
Byron always said the city spoke to him.
可以想见
I can relate to that.
你很像他
You're a lot like him.
他告诉你他是个罪犯的时候 你作何感想?
How did you feel when he told you he was a criminal?
很心痛
It hurt.
但我依然爱他
But I loved him.
他做过什么并不重要
And it didn't matter what he was.
重要的是他是什么样的人
It only mattered who he was.
我也希望我能将这二者区分
I wish I could separate the two.
时间会给你答案的
Well, you'll learn with time.
等一下
Just a second.
嘿 有新发现了?
Hey. Find something new?
- 嗯  - 太棒了
- Yeah.  - Great.
其实没有
No.
我是想假装发现了什么
I was gonna lie, pretend I found something,
但我只是想来看看你
but I just wanted to come see you.
无论现在我们之间算是什么关系
Whatever this is between us,
我... 我都不想停下来
I... I don't want it to stop.
我也不想
I don't either.
是吗?
Yeah?
但有件事你应该先知道
But there's something you should know about me.
好的
Okay.
我不是联邦调查局探员
I'm not an FBI agent.
我是个罪犯线人
I'm a criminal informant.
我因伪造债券被定罪
I was convicted of bond forgery
在成为罪犯线人之前
and served part of a four-year sentence
服过四年刑期的一部分
before I became a CI.
我... 我没明白
I'm... I don't understand.
我去过你的办公室
I've been to your office.
我一直与你的上司Gruetzner探员合作
I've been working with your boss, Agent Gruetzner.
他不是我的上司
Yeah, he's not my boss.
我真正的上司是Peter Burke 那天晚餐遇见的那位
My real boss is Peter Burke, who you met at dinner.
那个办公室只是事先布置好
That office was just a setup
为了让你帮忙破解法典的
to get your help with the codex.
你布置了一间假办公室以便向我撒谎?
You set up a fake office all so you could lie to me?
你到底是不是在研究法典啊?
Are you even researching the codex?
是的
I am.
只不过不是为联邦调查局调查
Just not for the FBI.
Rebecca啊
Rebecca.
你为什么这样对我?
Why would you do this to me?
我需要你的帮助
I needed your help, all right?
而我...
And I...
我没想到这件事
I didn't expect this.
我没想到我们会有进展
I didn't expect us.
还有什么别的瞒着我的吗?
Is there anything else I should know?
谢谢
Thank you.
我想我...
I think I was just...
June啊!
June!
是Neal啊!
Neal!
我刚才在和这位出色的男士聊天
I was just chatting with this wonderful man,
叫...
Mr...
叫我Curtis就好
You can call me "Curtis".
Curtis 好可爱的名字
Curtis. It's a lovely name.
谢谢
Thank you.
那...
Well, I think...
我就先走了
I'll just be running along.
Hagen 离她远点
You stay away from her, Hagen.
你的人生大楼还真不错
Quite the life you've built.
不想目睹一切因一小扇窗而崩塌
Hate to see things fall apart over one little window.
没错 我知道法典有线索指引到彩绘玻璃
That's right, I know that the codex leads to the window.
你已经在准备为我偷玻璃了 真是幸运不是吗?
Isn't it lucky you were already planning to steal it for me?
你一直都是这么计划的 对吧?
That was what you were planning, wasn't it?
- 当然  - 很好
- Of course.  - Good.
这样对大家都好
That would be best for everyone.